One of the ways that we can improve is by using content and ranked-based methods.
一种改进方式是使用基于内容和排名的方法
So, this part here is basically just reading
这部分将读取
in a couple of functions that we wrote before from the content-based metrics,
我们在基于内容的指标部分编写的几个函数
so finding similar movies based on movies that you've already given.
这个函数会根据你提供的电影查找相似电影
This function here is pulling the popular recommendations.
这个函数会提取热门推荐电影
So, our goal here is now to make
我们的目标是
recommendations using the collaborative filtering based method,
使用之前用过的协同过滤方法
as well as the content and popular based methods that we sort of have used before.
以及基于内容和热门电影的方法做出推荐
Trained data here, trained data df is a data frame,
这是训练数据 train_data_df 是一个 DataFrame
so let's just take a look at the header of this.
我们看看这个 DataFrame 的标头
This is basically our user movie combinations for all possible user movie combinations,
这个表格包含了所有可能的用户-电影组合
and what we want do is be able to make recommendations for every user in here.
我们希望对其中的每个用户做出推荐
So, if we can use Funk SVD to do it, we can do that.
如果能使用 Funk SVD 我们将使用它
If we can use a rank-based method, we could do that.
如果能使用排名方法 我们将使用它
So, basically what I'm going do is,
我将在这里
I'm going to create a two paths here.
分两部分编写代码
One is a recommendation based on the type of ID,
一部分基于 ID 类型进行推荐
and if the ID has a user,
如果 ID 表示用户
then I'm going to provide a different type of recommendation technique than if
那么推荐技巧将与提供电影 ID 后
you provide me an ID of a movie.
采用的推荐技巧不同
So, I essentially started by creating two potential methods for creating recommendations,
我首先创建了两个提供推荐内容的方法
and actually I'm want to finish
我先完成这部分
this one out because this one's actually pretty straightforward.
因为这部分比较简单
So, if you give me a movie recommendation,
如果你提供给我电影推荐
then I'm going to only use a content-based recommendation system.
那么我将仅使用基于内容的推荐系统
So, what I'm basically going to do is,
在这部分
I'm going to say are recommended IDs are just
推荐的 ID 将等于
based on finding similar movies to the idea that you gave me.
根据你提供的 ID 查找相似的电影
You are going to give me a movie ID,
你需要提供电影 ID
I'm going to find similar movies.
我将查找相似电影
I'm going to grab the names of those movies,
获取这些电影的片名
and I'm going to give them back to you okay,
并返回这些片名
and this finding similar movies is basically
这个 finding_similar_movies 函数
just the content based recommendation system that we use before.
是我们之前使用的基于内容的推荐系统
So, if you give me a movie ID,
如果你提供了电影 ID...
and I have this type variable up here.
在这里有个类型变量
So, basically if you give me a movie ID,
如果你提供了电影 ID
I'm going to find similar movies,
我将查找相似电影
and I'm going to recommend those movies to you.
并向你推荐这些电影
If you give me a user ID,
如果你提供了用户 ID
then there are multiple methods that I could use to make a prediction.
那么我可以使用多种方法做出推荐
I could use collaborative filtering.
我可以使用协同过滤
I could use a ranked-based system.
使用基于排名的系统
There are lots of things that you might choose to do with a user ID.
对于用户 ID 可以采用多种方法
So, the main thing that I did first was I went into the users,
首先我进入用户矩阵中
and I pulled the index.
并获取索引
So, I wanted to pull where this thing was,
我想知道它在什么位置
and we've actually used this a lot of times,
实际上我多次使用了这种索引方法
so I'm going to pull the index,
我将提取索引
and I'm going to store that.
并存储到变量中
Then, what I'm going to do is,
然后
I'm going to make a prediction based on
我将根据两项的点积做出预测
the dot-product of the user matrix where that user exists.
其中一个是用户矩阵
So, I'm going to grab their row and all of the columns.
我将获取用户所在的行和所有列
So, this is going to grab the row associated with that user from the user matrix,
这部分代码将从用户矩阵中获取与该用户相关的行
and I'm going to grab the entire movie matrix,
并获取整个电影矩阵
and I'm going to take the dot-product.
然后计算点积
What this is going to do is it's going to give me all of
它将提供该用户的每部电影
the predictions for the rating for every movie for that user,
对应的预测评分
so I'm going to take the dot-product of the user matrix with the movie matrix.
我将计算用户矩阵与电影矩阵的点积
But in the user matrix,
但是在用户矩阵中
I'm only going to grab the row associated with that user,
仅获取该用户所在的行
and then I'm going to take the dot-product with the movie matrix.
然后计算与电影矩阵的点积
So, this is essentially using Funk SVD to create a prediction,
也就是使用 Funk SVD 创建预测
and then what I'm going to do is I'm going to sort
然后根据从高到低顺序
those according to the highest predictions.
对预测排序
So, what this is going to do, is it's going to give me predicted ratings,
这样会获得预测评分
and I just want to grab the highest ones and give those back,
我只想获取并返回最高预测
so this was the way that I chose to make those predictions.
这就是我的预测方式
So, the way I grabbed the highest ones I use something called an argsort.
我使用了 argsort() 来获取最高预测评分
I sorted them, and then I pulled the however many recommendations they wanted.
对这些项排序 然后提取所需数量的推荐内容
I'm going to pull this out,
我将这部分代码单独拿出来
just so you can see what's happening here.
解释下代码的含义
The index is grabbing the row associated with this user in the user matrix.
Idx 获取的是用户矩阵中与此用户相关的行
If you give me the ID of 50,
如果 ID 等于 50
I'm going to go in and find that user in my user matrix,
我将从用户矩阵中找到该用户
and I'm going to pull that row.
并提取该行
I'm going to take the dot-product with the movie matrix,
然后计算它与用户矩阵的点积
and that's going to give me the predictions.
这样就会获得预测值
So, this is the prediction for the rating that that user would
这些评分是该用户对整个电影矩阵中的
give to every movie in the entire movie matrix.
每部电影的预测评分
Then, what this part does here,
这部分的作用是...
which I'm sure I use Stack Overflow to get,
我从 Stack Overflow 上找到了这些代码
what this part does here,
这部分的作用是
is it sorts those values and grabs the indices associated with those movies right.
对这些值排序并获取与这些电影相关的索引
So, what this does is it takes the predictions,
这部分会获取预测值
and we can look at this part here is probably the main thing.
将这部分代码单独拿出来
So, what this does is it sorts them according to the predicted value,
它会按照预测值排序
and then it gives me the index back.
并返回索引
Then, what this part does is it says,
这部分的作用是...
so if we look at this. Let's say negative 10.
传入一个数字例如 -10
What this does is it gives me the top ten back,
它会返回前 10 个值
and then basically what I'm doing next is,
接下来
I'm just flipping the order.
我将颠倒顺序
So, this colon, colon negative one is just flipping the order.
“::-1”的作用是颠倒顺序
If we look at this versus this part,
我们来看看这部分与这部分的区别
if you haven't seen this before,
如果你之前没见过的话 解释下
it's just a nice trick that says flip the order.
这是一种颠倒顺序的小技巧
So, before they were ordered this way,
之前顺序是这样的
now they're ordered this way, and that's just
现在顺序是这样的
important depending on how you're going to index into them.
顺序取决于之后如何通过索引访问它们
So, I must have decided later on that I wanted to index into them in a certain way,
因为我决定之后以特定的方式访问索引
and return them back in a certain order.
并以特定的顺序返回值 所以这么排序
So, this is just pulling the actual movie names, so train, data,
这部分将获取实际的片名
df.columns is the movie IDs,
Train_data_df.columns 是电影 ID
and this is the index associated with each movie ID.
这是与每个电影 ID 相关的索引
I'm pulling those movie IDs, and then I'm saying,
我提取出这些电影 ID
"Give me the movie names back for the movie IDs."
然后返回这些电影ID 对应的片名
So, I'm going to call this rec names here,
将这个称为 rec_names
and then basically these rec IDs and rec names are the same,
这些 rec_ids 和 rec_names 是一样的
except for one set,
只不过一个针对的是
is if you give me a movie ID,
提供电影 ID 的情形
and the other set is if you give me a user ID.
另一个针对的是提供用户 ID 的情形
I noticed with this particular method that a lot of
我发现在使用这个方法时
my predictions ended up looking the same across lots of different users,
有很多用户的预测是一样的
and so maybe that's very accurate in terms of like lots of users would like those movies.
也许这很准确 因为很多用户都喜欢这些电影
But in terms of some of the other criteria like
但是从其他标准的角度来说
serendipity or finding things that are sort of nostalgic,
我的推荐系统并不是太好
my particular recommendation system wouldn't do that very well.
例如意外新发现或发现怀旧电影
So, with that, I wish you luck in making your own recommendation system,
希望你能自己创建一个推荐系统
and I hope this was insightful in terms of how I could combine both a
这些就是我结合基于内容的推荐方法和 Funk SVD 方法
content-based and a Funk SVD method to make predictions for users and movies like.
为用户和电影做出预测的流程 希望能对你有所启发